来自 Random Infoboy 的亲爱的朋友们欢迎来到这批特别的作品
My dear friends from Random Infoboy welcome to this special batch
Mis queridos amigos de Random Infoboy bienvenidos a esta tanda especial
与伟大的亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特 (Alexis McAllister) 一起在 AFA Selección 工作室。
here in the AFA Selección studios with the great Alexis McAllister.
acá en los estudios de AFA Selección con el gran Alexis McAllister.
欢迎。
Welcome.
Bienvenido.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
感谢有我们，有你，Nico，Dadi，所有的现象。
Thank you for having us, you, Nico, Dadi, all phenomena.
Gracias por recibirnos, vos, Nico, Dadi, todos unos fenómenos.
他们对我们很好，所以我很荣幸能够和你聊天。
They have treated us excellently, so it is an honor for me to be able to chat with you.
Nos han tratado excelente, así que para mí es un honor poder charlar con vos.
你好吗？
How are you doing?
¿Cómo andás?
嗯，非常感谢。
Well, thank you very much.
Bueno, muchas gracias.
我也很高兴能和你们在一起。
It is also a pleasure for me to be here with you.
Para mí es un placer también estar acá con ustedes.
好，好。
Good, good.
Bien, bien.
现在休息了一会儿，我们有时间和家人一起享受。
Now resting a little, we had our time to enjoy with the family.
Ya descansando un poquito, tuvimos nuestro tiempo para disfrutar con la familia.
现在关注2024年的最后一场比赛。
Now focus on the last game of 2024.
ahora ya enfocarse en el último partido del 2024.
我们在布宜诺斯艾利斯的 AFA 场地处于集中模式，所以它混合了他们在那里有一些时间与家人一起去，我说的是人们不知道的事情。
We are in concentration mode at the AFA grounds, Buenos Aires, everything, so it mixes that there they have some time to go with the family, I say things that people don't know.
Estamos en modo concentración en el predio de AFA, Buenos Aires, todo, entonces se mezcla que por ahí tienen un rato para ir con la familia, digo por ahí cosas que la gente no sabe.
来来去去，集中注意力，但有一点时间呆在家里，这很好。
It's good that it's good to come and go, to be focused but to have a little time to spend at home.
está bueno eso hace bien el ir y venir estar concentrado pero tener un ratito para pasar por casa
我总是这么说，我总是说要有莱昂内尔，他是一名足球运动员。
And I always said it, I always said that having Lionel, who was a soccer player.
Y yo siempre lo dije, siempre dije que tenerlo a Lionel, que fue jugador de fútbol.
谁知道每次来到布宜诺斯艾利斯等地时与家人在一起意味着什么。
who knows what it means to have your family close every time you come to Buenos Aires and so on.
que sabe lo que significa tener a la familia cerca cada vez que venís a Buenos Aires y demás.
很好，很好。
It's good, it's good.
Está bueno, está bueno.
以我们为例，我觉得世界杯对我们帮助很大。
For us, for example, I feel that in the World Cup it helped us a lot.
A nosotros, por ejemplo, yo siento que en el Mundial nos ayudó un montón.
我们可以在卡塔尔见到我们的家人，与我们一起度过这一天。
that we could see our families there in Qatar, to spend the day with us.
que podíamos ver a nuestras familias allá en Qatar, a pasar el día con nosotros.
对我来说，这是非常重要的事情，我们很幸运，正如我告诉过你的，老师也是如此。
For me it is something that is very important and we are lucky, as I told you, so is the teacher.
Para mí es algo que es muy importante y tenemos la suerte, como te digo, el profe también.
为我们奋斗一点，试着给我们自由的时刻。
fight a little for us, try to give us our free moments.
pelea un poco para nosotros, intenta darnos nuestros momentos libres.
我们尝试享受一点。
that we try to enjoy a little.
que nosotros intentamos disfrutar un poquito.
听我说，你今天过得怎么样？
Listen to me, how are you today?
Escúchame, ¿cómo estás hoy?
幸福程度。
Degree of happiness.
Grado de felicidad.
在英超踢球，阿根廷国家队，两届美国冠军，你醒了，你醒了。
playing in the Premier, Argentine national team, two-time champion of America, you woke up, you woke up.
jugando en la Premier, selección argentina, bicampeón de América, te levantaste, te amaneciste.
我是多么恶心，因为我不不不但是
how gross I am as I am no no no but
qué grosso soy como estoy no no no pero
显然，看到幸福是非常伟大的，自豪感高于一切，因为……
obviously to see happiness is very great, pride above all, because one...
obviamente a ver la felicidad es muy grande, el orgullo sobre todo, porque uno...
他努力工作以达到他所在的位置。
He works hard to be where he is.
trabaja mucho para estar en el lugar en el que está.
好吧，一切都发生得很快，我想在两年、两年半的时间内。
And well, everything happened quite quickly, I think in a period of two years, two and a half years.
Y bueno, se dio todo bastante rápido, creo que en un lapso de dos años, dos años y medio.
一切都发生了。
Everything happened.
Pasó de todo.
今天，我发现自己在欧洲最大的俱乐部之一为一支世界冠军球队效力。
Today I find myself playing in one of the biggest clubs in Europe for a world champion team.
Hoy me encuentro jugando en uno de los clubes más grandes de Europa para una selección campeona del mundo.
我试着享受它，事实上，我玩得很开心。
I try to enjoy it and well, the truth is that I am having a good time.
que intento disfrutarlo y bueno, la verdad que lo estoy pasando bien.
你如何吸收这一切？
And how do you assimilate all that?
¿Y cómo asimilas todo eso?
因为你是，你今天几岁了？
Because you are, how old are you today?
Porque sos, ¿qué edad tenés hoy?
今天我25岁了。
And today I am 25.
Y hoy tengo 25.
当然，你还很年轻。
Of course, you are very young.
Claro, sos muy joven.
不知道你知不知道，你还很年轻。
I don't know if you know that you are very young.
No sé si vos sabés que sos muy joven.
我，比你年长的人告诉你，你还很年轻。
I, who am older than you, tell you, you are very young.
Yo que soy más viejo que vos te digo, sos muy joven.
但当然，三四年后，一切都在一起，李子，就像那样。
But of course, in three or four years, all together, plum, like that.
Pero claro, en tres o cuatro años, todos juntos, plum, así.
是的，这很难。
Yes, it's difficult.
Sí, es difícil.
它很难。
It's difficult.
Es difícil.
我相信足球有一种无法打败你的动力。
I believe that football has a dynamic that cannot defeat you.
Yo creo que el fútbol tiene una dinámica que no te puede.
停下来想一想你所取得的成就。
Stop and think a little about what you are achieving.
parar a pensar un poco lo que estás logrando.
我想刚才...
I think just now...
Yo creo que recién ahora...
我开始对世界杯等一切事情感到有些失落。
I'm starting to fall a little bit from everything that was the World Cup and so on.
Estoy empezando a caer un poco de todo lo que fue el Mundial y demás.
正如我告诉你的那样，一切都进行得很快，你赢得了世界杯，10 天后你必须与你的球队一起亮相，继续比赛，然后是美洲杯。
As I tell you, everything goes very quickly, you win a World Cup and after 10 days you have to present with your team, continue playing, then the Copa América.
Como te digo, va todo muy rápido, ganas un Mundial y a los 10 días tenés que presentar con tu equipo, seguir jugando, después la Copa América.
所以很难停下来。
So it's difficult to stop.
Entonces es complicado frenarse.
但好吧，我想...
But well, I think...
Pero bueno, creo que...
我在其他事情上也看到了这一点。
With other things I'm seeing it.
con otras cosas lo voy viendo.
例如，前几天...
For example, the other day...
Por ejemplo, el otro día...
Pinto 伴随着一级方程式赛车而来，你看到了吗？
With the Pinto comes Formula 1, did you see?
Con la Pinto llega la Fórmula 1, ¿viste?
就好像我不感兴趣，我不太看一级方程式赛车。
And it's like I wasn't interested, I didn't watch Formula 1 much.
Y es como que a mí no me interesaba, no lo veía mucho la Fórmula 1.
现在我说，或者有一个阿根廷人，他看起来不错。
And now I say, or there is an Argentine, he looks good.
Y ahora digo, o hay un argentino, está con la pinta.
让我们看一级方程式赛车，明白吗？
Let's watch Formula 1, you understand?
Vamos a ver la Fórmula 1, ¿entendés?
我或多或少地将它与我们的联系起来。
And I more or less connect it a little with ours.
Y más o menos lo conecto un poco con lo nuestro.
告诉你，例如，他们看到了宫内节育器，今天每个人都告诉你，不，男孩们都想成为弓箭手。
to tell you, for example, that they see the IUD, that today everyone tells you, no, the boys all want to be archers.
de deciros, por ejemplo, que lo vean al DIU, que hoy todos te dicen, no, los chicos quieren ser todos arqueros.
就像通过这些小细节你开始意识到我们正在产生什么。
And it's like with those small details you start realizing what we are generating.
Y es como que con esos pequeños detalles te vas dando cuenta de lo que vamos generando.
它所具有的维度。
The dimension it has.
La dimensión que tiene.
我们所产生的选择，无论是个性，就像我告诉你的关于 DIBU 的例子。
what we are generating as a selection, be it individualities, as I told you about DIBU, for example.
lo que vamos generando como selección ya sea individualidades como te digo lo del DIBU por ejemplo
或其他。
or others.
o demás.
也没什么，我觉得挺好的。
And nothing, I think it's good.
Y nada, creo que está bueno.
但我认为这需要时间，也许明天我们从足球界退役并看到我们所取得的一切。
But I think it will take time and maybe tomorrow when we retire from football and see everything we achieved.
pero creo que nos va a llevar su tiempo y quizás en el día de mañana cuando nos retiremos del fútbol y veamos todo lo que logramos.
这将变得更加重要。
It's going to be more important.
va a ser más importante.
当你稍微退一步，如果你完全退一步，我不知道你是否是一个反思的人。
When you pull back a little bit, if you pull back at all, I don't know if you are one to reflect.
Cuando tiras un poquito para atrás, si es que tiras para atrás, no sé si sos de reflexionar.
博卡的离开，当时的一些争议，布莱顿的离开……
The departure of Boca, some controversies at the time, Brighton leaves...
La salida de Boca, algunas controversias en su momento, se va el Brighton...
那一刻你以为一切都会在利物浦结束
You imagined at that moment that this was going to end in Liverpool
vos imaginabas en ese momento que esto iba a terminar en el Liverpool
你必须离开去英超踢球，更高的一步即将到来。
that you had to leave to play in the Premier League, that a higher step was going to come.
que vos tenías que irte para jugar la Premier, que iba a venir un escalón superior.
让我们看看，发生在我身上的一切很难想象和梦想，对吗？
Let's see, it's hard to imagine and dream everything that happened to me, right?
A ver, difícil imaginar y soñar todo lo que me pasó, ¿no?
但是，是的，显然，当你做出这些决定时，背后的一切，发生的一切......
But yes, obviously, when you make those kinds of decisions, with everything behind it, everything that happened...
Pero sí, obviamente, cuando uno toma esa clase de decisiones, con todo lo que hay detrás, todo lo que pasó...
当你做出此类决定时，你总是会考虑改进。
When you make those kinds of decisions, you always think about improving.
Cuando uno toma esa clase de decisiones, uno siempre piensa en mejorar.
那一刻我并没有想太多，我要成为世界冠军，我要为利物浦效力。
At that moment I didn't think so much about, I'm going to be world champion, I'm going to play for Liverpool.
Yo no lo pensaba en ese momento tanto de, voy a ser campeón del mundo, voy a jugar para el Liverpool.
但这是个人进步、体验新文化的重要一步。
But it was an important step to improve as a person, to experience new cultures.
Pero sí era un paso importante para mejorar tanto como persona, vivir nuevas culturas.
其他国家，另一种语言，成为一名更好的足球运动员。
other countries, another language, being a better soccer player.
otros países, otro idioma, ser mejor jugador de fútbol.
我觉得这一步对我来说是最重要的一步。
I feel that that step was one of the most important for me.
Yo siento que ese paso fue uno de los más importantes para mí.
我总是这么说，我对布莱顿有着特殊的感情。
I always say it, I have a special affection for Brighton.
Siempre lo digo, tengo un cariño especial por Brighton.
他们给了我机会……蹦床！
They were the ones who gave me the possibility of... The trampoline!
Fueron los que me dieron la posibilidad de... ¡El trampolín!
现状如此，现状如此。
As is, as is.
Tal cual, tal cual.
利物浦有多强？
And how good are Liverpool?
¿Y qué tan bueno está el Liverpool?
不，利物浦是……正如人们所想的那样。
No, Liverpool is... For what people think.
No, Liverpool es... Para lo que la gente piensa.
不，利物浦疯了。
No, Liverpool is crazy.
No, Liverpool es una locura.
换句话说，无论你需要什么，无论你想要什么......
In other words, whatever you need, whatever you want...
O sea, vos lo que necesites, lo que quieras...
让我们一点一点地来。
Let's go little by little.
Vamos de a poco.
什么是疯狂？
What is crazy?
¿Qué es una locura?
人员、设施、场地……
The people, the facilities, the field...
La gente, las instalaciones, la cancha...
一切？
¿Everything?
¿Todo?
一切。
Everything.
Todo.
事实是，正如我告诉你的那样，对我来说，这是世界上最大的俱乐部之一。
The truth is that, as I tell you, for me, one of the biggest clubs in the world.
La verdad que, como te digo, para mí, uno de los clubes más grandes del mundo.
设施是一流的，工作人员也是一流的。
The facilities are top-notch, the people who work are top-notch.
Las instalaciones son de primer nivel, la gente que trabaja es de primer nivel.
英格兰最好的球迷，说实话，没有什么值得的……
the fans of the best in England, honestly there is not much for...
la hinchada de las mejores de Inglaterra, sinceramente no hay mucho por lo...
所以抱怨。
so complain.
por lo que quejarse.
正如我所说，我真的很喜欢它，我很高兴来到这里。
As I say, I really enjoy it, I'm very happy to be here.
Como te digo, disfruto mucho, estoy muy contento de estar aquí.
你必须打得好，仅此而已。
You have to play well and nothing more.
Tienes que jugar bien y nada más.
是的，显然，压力是存在的。
Yes, obviously, the pressure is on.
Sí, obviamente, la presión está.
由于这是一支如此大的球队，压力很大，冠军们也想要这样的压力。
As it is such a big team, the pressure is on, the titles want it.
Como es un equipo tan grande, la presión está, los títulos lo quieren.
好吧，我们正在寻找这个。
And well, we are looking for that.
Y bueno, estamos en busca de eso.
你提出了一个很好的话题，压力。
You brought up a good topic, pressure.
Buen tema me tiraste, la presión.
我们一直在谈论篮球、足球、压力、压力、压力。
We talk all the time about basketball, football, pressure, pressure, pressure.
Todo el tiempo hablamos del básquet, del fútbol, de la presión, la presión, la presión.
您如何应对压力以及压力对您意味着什么？
How do you handle it and what does pressure mean to you?
¿Cómo la manejas y qué significa para vos la presión?
无论是好是坏，我相信压力
and if in any case it is good or bad, I believe that the pressure
y si en todo caso es bueno o malo, yo creo que la presión
知道你背后有这么多人支持，这取决于......
It is knowing that you have so many people behind you that it depends on...
es el saber que tenés a tanta gente detrás que por ahí depende de...
无论是从选择中，还是从俱乐部中。
be it from a selection, be it from a club.
sea de una selección, sea de un club.
并且知道背后有这么多人可以......
and knowing that there are so many people behind it that could...
y saber que hay tanta gente detrás de eso que capaz que...
他把钱花在这件事上，他花了很多时间在这件事上或其他事情上。
He spends his money on that, he spends so much time on that or something else.
gasta su plata en eso, que invierte tanto tiempo en eso o demás.
我认为这是你能感受到的一点压力。
I think that's a bit of the pressure you can feel.
Creo que eso es un poco la presión que se puede llegar a sentir.
但事实是，我从来没有受过这么多的苦，我从来没有受过这么多的苦。
But the truth is that I never suffered it so much, I never suffered it so much.
pero yo la verdad que nunca la sufrí tanto, nunca la sufrí tanto.
我总是尽力享受这个地方......
I always try to enjoy the place...
Siempre intento disfrutar del lugar...
我认为这是减轻压力的一个非常重要的部分，最终知道......
I think that is a very important part of taking off the pressure of finally knowing that...
creo que eso es una parte muy importante para sacarse la presión de al final saber que...
后面的一切都是这一切的一部分，你只需要担心踢足球。
that everything that is behind is part of this and that you simply have to worry about playing football.
que todo lo que está atrás es parte de esto y que vos simplemente tenés que preocuparte por jugar al fútbol.
那么在这种情况下，利物浦将再次作为一个俱乐部进入。
And well in that case Liverpool enters again as a club.
Y bueno en ese caso entra otra vez Liverpool como club.
从这个意义上说，他们在所有事情上都会帮助你。
that in that sense they help you in everything.
que ellos en ese sentido te ayudan en todo.
所以，你有你需要的一切，你不必担心踢足球。
So, you have whatever you need and you have to worry about playing football.
Entonces, vos lo que necesites lo tenés y vos tenés que preocuparte por jugar al fútbol.
你学到了什么？
And what did you learn?
Y ¿qué aprendiste?
因为精英运动员，超级有名，有很多钱。
Because elite athlete, super famous, a lot of money.
Porque deportista elite, súper recontra famoso, mucho dinero.
你必须管理它，你必须把自己包围得很好，你必须投资。
You have to manage it, you have to surround yourself well, you have to invest.
hay que manejarlo, hay que rodearse bien, hay que invertir.
你从那些事情中学到东西了吗？
Did you learn things from those?
¿Aprendiste cosas de esas?
参与你的足球，额外的足球，但是足球给你带来了什么？
to get involved with yours, extra football, but what does football give you?
de involucrarte con lo tuyo, extra fútbol, pero que el fútbol te da?
是的，让我们看看。
Yes, let's see.
Sí, a ver.
如果我们谈论...
If we talk about...
Si hablamos de...
在我的环境中，显然我很幸运有一个家庭
Of everything that is my environment, obviously I am lucky to have a family that
de todo lo que es mi ambiente, obviamente yo tengo la suerte de tener una familia que
谁在这个世界上，谁知道它是如何运作的。
who was in this world, who knows how it works.
que estuvo en este mundo, que sabe cómo funciona.
对于足球之外的一切事情，我总是能得到帮助，但这也许有点
With everything that is extra-football I always have help and it is perhaps a little
con todo lo que es lo extrafutbolístico siempre tengo una ayuda y es quizás un poco
更容易，显然我每天都喜欢学习。
easier, obviously every day I like to learn.
más fácil, obviamente que todos los días me gusta aprender.
不管是什么，最重要的是参与属于我的事情。
Whatever it is, get involved in the things that are mine, above all.
sea lo que sea, involucrarme en las cosas que son mías, sobre todo.
但是，感谢上帝，正如我所说，我有一个总是给我很多帮助的家庭。
But well, thank God, as I said, I have a family that always helped me a lot.
Pero bueno gracias a Dios como te digo tengo una familia que siempre me ayudó muchísimo.
老科洛麦卡利斯特能给建议吗？
Does old Colo Macalister give advice?
¿El viejo Colo Macalister da consejos?
总是。
Always.
Siempre.
你爸爸？
Your dad?
¿Tu papá?
既提出建议，又提出批评。
Gives advice and criticizes, both.
Da consejos y critica, las dos.
你生气了，伙计...
You're mad, dude...
Te caga pedo, tipo...
这对你来说很重要还是很困难？
Is it critical or is it hard for you?
¿Es crítico bien o te da duro?
不，很好，很好。
No, good, good.
No, bien, bien.
他尝试...
He tries...
Él intenta...
显然我们是他的孩子，我想这对他来说一定有点困难。
Obviously we are his children and I imagine it must be a little difficult for him.
Obviamente somos sus hijos y me imagino que para él debe ser un poco difícil.
批评我们，但他总是尽量现实、诚实、说实话。
criticize us but he always tries to be realistic, be honest, tell the truth.
criticarnos pero él siempre intenta ser realista, ser honesto, decir la verdad.
然后从中我们看看是否...
and then from that we see if...
y después a nosotros a partir de eso vemos si...
不管我们是否同意他的观点，我们都可以改进一些东西，因为有时当他提出意见时，我们说不，我们就是这样。
There is something we can improve, whether we agree with him or not, because there are times when he gives an opinion, we say no, that's how it is for us.
hay algo que podamos mejorar, si coincidimos con él o no, porque hay veces que él da una opinión, nosotros decimos no, para nosotros es así.
嗯，一段愉快的对话就这样产生了，这很有趣。
And well, a nice conversation is generated, which is interesting.
Y bueno, se genera una conversación linda, que es interesante.
他们经常谈论足球吗？
Do they talk a lot about football?
¿Hablan mucho de fútbol?
是的，一直如此。
Yes, all the time.
Sí, todo el tiempo.
而萨多斯则不太熟悉，因为既然我们都分开了，现在凯文在墨西哥，弗朗西在阿根廷，我在英格兰，哈维尔……
And Sados is not so familiar, because since we are all separated, now there is Kevin in Mexico, Franci in Argentina, me in England and Javier...
Y a Sados familiar no tanto, porque como estamos todos separados, ahora está Kevin en México, Franci en Argentina, yo en Inglaterra y Javier...
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
那里，到处。
There, everywhere.
Ahí, por todos lados.
但我们确实有一个 WhatsApp 群组，而且一直都有。
But we do have a WhatsApp group and, well, always.
Pero sí tenemos un grupo de WhatsApp y, bueno, siempre.
WhatsApp 很熟悉。
WhatsApp familiar.
是的，是的，就我们四个人，仅此而已，我们平常说话的地方。
Yes, yes, there are the four of us, nothing more, where we generally talk.
Sí, sí, ahí nosotros cuatro, nada más, donde se habla generalmente.
足球，总是祝我们好运，观看比赛，评论比赛。
football, always wishing us luck, watching the games, commenting on the games.
de fútbol, siempre deseándonos suerte, viendo los partidos, comentando sobre los partidos.
所以从这个意义上说，我们得到了支持。
So in that sense we have support.
Así que en ese sentido tenemos apoyo.
听着，我们已经知道你有多优秀了。
Listen, we already know how good you are.
Escucha, ya sabemos todo lo bueno que sos.
为自己25岁时的愿景，在利物浦国家队，冠军，蒂蒂蒂蒂蒂蒂。
for your own vision at 25 years old, in Liverpool National Team, champion, titi titi titi.
para tu propia visión a los 25 años, en Liverpool Selección, campeón, titi titi titi.
作为一名球员你还缺少什么？
What are you missing as a player?
¿Qué te falta como jugador?
不，很多。
No, a lot.
No, un montón.
那？
That?
¿Qué?
你不喜欢你的游戏的哪些方面？
What don't you like about your game?
¿Qué no te gusta de tu juego?
还有我的游戏...
And well as for my game...
Y bueno en cuanto a mi juego...
我认为今天，在像英超这样的联赛中，这是我一直拥有的东西......我的意思是，让我们看看......
I think that today, being in a league as physical as the Premier League, it is something that I always have... I mean, let's see...
Yo creo que hoy, estando en una liga tan física como es la Premier League, es algo que siempre tengo... O sea, a ver...
我感觉很好，我觉得我已经达到了我需要的水平，但这总是可以改进的。
I feel good, I feel that I am at the level I need, but it is something that can always be improved.
Me siento bien, siento que estoy al nivel que necesito, pero es algo que siempre se puede mejorar.
最明显的例子就是萨拉赫，他就在我身边，他是一个
and I have the clearest example in Salah, who is at my side and he is a person who
y yo tengo el ejemplo más claro en Salah que lo tengo al lado y él es una persona que
谁有心态，谁有体质。
who has a mentality and has a physique.
que tiene una mentalidad y tiene un físico.
他因他所做的事情而拥有它。
that he has it for the things he does.
que lo tiene por las cosas que hace.
我尝试复制这类东西。
I try to copy that kind of thing.
intento copiar esa clase de cosas.
但总有一些事情需要改进，我告诉你身体上的，但也......
But there are always things to improve, I tell you physically, but also...
Pero siempre hay cosas por mejorar, te digo lo físico, pero también...
我真的很喜欢理解这个游戏，知道我要去哪里，按原样阅读它。
I really like to understand the game, know where I have to go, read it as it is.
A mí me gusta mucho entender el juego, saber para dónde tengo que ir, leerlo tal cual.
这需要一段时间，对吧？
That takes a while, right?
Eso tarda, ¿no?
这很复杂。
And that's complicated.
Y eso es complicado.
我很幸运拥有优秀的技术人员。
I was lucky to have great technicians.
Yo tuve la suerte de tener grandes técnicos.
他们在这方面帮助了我很多。
They helped me a lot to improve that aspect.
que me ayudaron un montón a mejorar ese aspecto.
我为你命名它们。
and I name them for you.
y te los nombre.
我有海因策，我有罗伯托·德·塞维奥，一个意大利人……
I had Heinze, I had Roberto de Servio, an Italian who...
Tuve a Heinze, tuve a Roberto de Servio, un italiano que...
对我来说，这是我拥有的最好的。
For me it was the best I had.
Para mí fue el mejor que tuve.
他们教会我从另一个方面理解足球。
They taught me to understand football from another side.
Me enseñaron a entender el fútbol desde otro lado.
在战术上，了解你的队友在哪里，很多事情。
tactically, knowing where your teammates are, a lot of things.
de lo táctico, de saber dónde están tus compañeros, un montón de cosas.
但我始终相信这些事情是可以改进的。
But I always believe that those kinds of things can be improved.
Pero yo siempre creo que se puede mejorar esa clase de cosas.
我仍然处于这个过程中，我想我会一直这样，直到我踢球的最后一天。
I am still in that process and I think I will be until the last day I play football.
Estoy todavía en ese proceso y creo que lo voy a estar hasta el último día que juega al fútbol.
听我说，说到老师，你踢球的不是别人，就是梅西，对吧？
Listen to me, speaking of teachers, you play with none other than Messi, right?
Escuchame, hablando de maestros, jugás nada menos que con Messi, ¿no?
我总是对你们如此精英的观点感兴趣
I am always interested from the point of view of you who are so elite
siempre me interesa desde el punto de vista de ustedes que son tan élite
当我听到这些粗鲁的人说他是最好的时，这是最好的，每个人都这么说。
When I hear such rude guys say he is the best, this is the best and everyone says that.
cuando escucho a tipos tan grosos decir él es el mejor, este es el mejor y que todos digan eso.
作为一名出色的足球运动员，您在训练或比赛中看到这个家伙是否感到惊讶......
Are you surprised in training or in games, being such a good footballer yourself, to see that the guy...
¿A vos te asombra en los entrenamientos o en los partidos, siendo tan bueno vos como futbolista también, ver que el chabón...
它能做我做不到的事情还是没人能做的事情？
Does it do things I can't do or does it do things no one can do?
¿Hace cosas que yo no puedo hacer o hace cosas que nadie puede hacer?
他们为什么会这样？
Why are they like this?
¿Por qué están así?
不，我认为他...
No, I think he...
No, yo creo que él...
显然，它被魔杖触碰了。
It's touched by the wand, obviously.
Está tocada por la varita, obviamente.
我想他是这么说的...
I think he said it...
Yo creo que él lo dijo...
上帝给了他这一切。
that God gave him all that.
que Dios le dio todo eso.
好吧，他试图利用这一点，让我们看看。
And well, he tries to take advantage of it, let's see.
Y bueno, él intenta aprovecharlo, a ver.
没有太多的言语来形容它。
There are not many words to describe it.
No hay muchas palabras para describirlo.
我的意思是，我问你的这件事就不能解释一下吗？
I mean, can't this thing I'm asking you be explained?
O sea, ¿no se puede explicar esto que te pregunto?
不，我认为这是甚至没有练习或改进的东西。
No, I think it is something that is not even practiced or improved.
No, yo creo que es algo que ni siquiera se practica o se mejora.
他就这样从工厂出来……
He came like this from the factory and...
Él vino así de fábrica y...
嗯，他很幸运能够……
And well, he was lucky enough to be...
Y bueno, tuvo esa suerte de ser...
为了成为最好的，他还添加了很多东西，使他变得更加强大。
to be the best and to that he added a lot of things that made him even bigger.
de ser el mejor y a eso le agregó un montón de cosas, que eso lo hicieron todavía más grande.
尤其是在这么多时间里取得成就的心态。
especially the mentality of achieving things in so much time.
sobre todo la mentalidad de lograr cosas en tanto tiempo.
我和我的老人有过这样的谈话。
I had this talk with my old man.
Yo tenía esta charla con mi viejo.
我什至现在在利物浦和俱乐部的人一起讨论过这个问题
I even had it now in Liverpool with people from the club where it was debated
incluso la tuve ahora en Liverpool con gente del club donde se debatía
更好的马拉多纳、梅西……是的，总是一样的。
Better Maradona, Messi... Yes, always the same.
Mejor Maradona, Messi... Sí, siempre lo mismo.
事实是，大多数人告诉你，梅西把它保留了 15 年、20 年。
And the thing is that most people tell you, Messi kept it for 15, 20 years.
Y el tema es que la mayoría te dice, Messi lo mantuvo por 15, 20 años.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
这并不是一件容易的事。
And that is not an easy thing.
Y eso no es algo fácil.
你看到的球员...
You see players who...
Vos ves jugadores que...
嗯，事实上，赢得世界杯的球员，两年后就退役了。
Well, in fact, players who have won the World Cup, who are retired after two years.
Bueno, de hecho jugadores que han ganado Mundial, que a los dos años están retirados.
他们找不到动力，而利奥总是发现......
They don't find that motivation and Leo always found that...
que no encuentran esa motivación y Leo siempre encontró esa...
那种想要成为最好的、想要享受、想要踢好足球的动力，我认为这就是让他变得伟大的原因。
that motivation of wanting to be the best, of wanting to enjoy, to play football and well, I think that's what makes him great.
esa motivación de querer ser el mejor, de querer disfrutar, de jugar al fútbol y bueno, creo que eso es lo que lo hace más grande.
那是勒布朗·乔丹、费德勒、纳达尔·约科维奇、汤姆·布雷迪、梅西……
That's LeBron Jordan, Federer, Nadal Jokovic, Tom Brady, Messi...
Esa es LeBron Jordan, Federer, Nadal Jokovic, Tom Brady, Messi...
20年来你一直保持这么好的水平，很不正常。
It is abnormal that for 20 years you have such a good level all the time.
Es anormal que durante 20 años tengas tan buen nivel todo el tiempo.
是的，是的，就是这样，这是不正常的。
Yes, yes, as is, which is abnormal.
Sí, sí, tal cual, que es anormal.
正如我所说，我相信......
And as I say, I believe that...
Y como te digo, yo creo que...
有一个部分是他们被魔杖触碰了，这给了他们天赋。
There is a part where they were touched by the wand, which gave them the talent.
Hay una parte donde ellos fueron tocados por la varita, que le dieron el talento.
还有一个非常非常重要的部分就是他们的心态。
and there is another very very important part which is the mentality that they have.
y hay otra parte muy muy importante que es la mentalidad que ellos tienen.
听着，另一个话题。
Listen, another topic.
Escucha, otro tema.
是的，我会在上面做，但我想制造这种感觉。
Yes, I'll do it above but I want to make this sensation.
Sí, te lo hago por arriba pero quiero hacer esta sensación.
如果你和女朋友分手了，如果你有了新女朋友，如果你有快乐……
If you broke up with a girlfriend, if you have a new girlfriend, if you have joy...
Si te separaste una novia, si tenés novia nueva, si tenés gozo...
成为一名精英运动员意味着什么，当你看到人们在其他领域谈论你时，你会说……
What it means to be an elite athlete, when you see people talking about you in other areas and you say...
Lo que conlleva ser un deportista elite, cuando vos te ves que hablan de vos en otros ámbitos y decís...
奥帕，我是一个节目的头条新闻，而不是足球节目的头条新闻。
Opa, I'm in a headline for a show program and not a football one.
Opa, estoy en un titular de un programa de espectáculo y no de fútbol.
你是如何吸收这一点的？
How did you assimilate that?
¿Cómo asimilaste eso?
你是怎么熬过来的？
How did you get through it?
¿Cómo lo atravesaste?
好吧，没有人给你一本如何在生活中处理自己的手册，你自己学习。
Well, no one gives you the manual on how to handle yourself in life, you learn it on your own.
Pues nadie te da el manual de cómo manejarte en la vida, lo vas aprendiendo solo.
你是怎么发生的以及发生了什么？
How and what happened to you?
¿Cómo y qué te pasó?
不，让我们看看，显然我不喜欢它。
No, let's see, obviously I don't like it.
No, a ver, obviamente no me gusta.
我不喜欢出现在足球以外的任何其他领域。
I don't like to appear in any other field other than football.
No me gusta aparecer en otro ámbito que no sea el de fútbol.
因为我出生在一个足球家庭，所以我以踢足球为生，这是我喜欢的，也是我感到舒服的地方。
Because I was born in a football family, I live playing football and it is what I like and where I feel comfortable.
Porque yo nací en una familia de fútbol, vivo jugando al fútbol y es lo que me gusta y donde me siento cómodo.
显然这根本不好，但最终
So obviously it's not good at all, but in the end
Entonces obviamente que no está para nada bueno, pero al final
我明白，因为我们所做的事情，因为我们所取得的成就……
I understand that because of what we do, because of what we have achieved...
Entiendo que por lo que hacemos nosotros, por lo que hemos logrado...
我们也接触到很多东西。
We are also exposed to a lot of things.
También estamos expuestos a un montón de cosas.
我总是笑，因为我相信如果我没有成为世界冠军，没有人会谈论我的处境，也不会产生任何结果。
I always laugh because I believe that if I had not been world champion, no one would have talked about my situation and nothing would have come of it.
Yo siempre me río porque yo creo que si no hubiese sido campeón del mundo, nadie hubiese hablado sobre mi situación y nada hubiese salido.
让我们看看你是否会检查一下你们是否在约会，是否打过架，是否分手了。
Let's see if you would check if you are dating, if you had a fight, if you broke up.
A ver si te fijarías si estás de novio, si te peleaste, si te separaste.
但是，嘿，你们是民族英雄、偶像。
But hey, you are national heroes, idols.
Pero bueno, ustedes son héroes nacionales, ídolos.
而且它比其他的影响更大。
and it has more impact than others.
y tiene más repercusión que otros.
是的，它没有用，但显然我认为我们对我们所取得的成就有很大的了解。
Yes, it is not useful, but yes obviously I think we have a very great exposure for what we have achieved.
Sí, no se sirve, pero sí obviamente creo que tenemos una exposición muy grande por lo que hemos logrado.
嗯，这是其中的一部分，一切都很好。
And well, it's part of this, it's all good.
Y bueno, es parte de esto, está todo bien.
如果你问我，就把世界杯给我吧。
If you ask me, give me the world cup.
Si me lo preguntás, dame la copa del mundo.
我保持原样。
I leave it as it is.
Lo dejo así como está.
但你也学习。
But you also learn.
Pero se aprende también.
我不知道是否有什么需要学习的，如果你犯了错误，我的意思是，你要学会吸收它。
I don't know if there is something to learn, if you made a mistake, I mean, you learn to assimilate that.
No sé si hay algo que aprender, si cometiste algún error, o sea, se aprende a asimilar eso.
是的，是的，显然。
Yes, yes, obviously.
Sí, sí, obvio.
不，显然。
No, obviously.
No, obvio.
我，让我们看看...
I, let's see...
Yo, a ver...
我总是这么说，从很小的时候起，我就一直希望人们谈论我们。
I always said it, from a very young age I always wanted people to talk about us.
Yo siempre lo dije, desde muy chico siempre me banqué que hablen de nosotros.
或者你可以玩，因为你是……哦，当然。
or yours to play because you are the son of... Oh, of course.
o de vos jugar porque sos el hijo de... Ah, claro.
从小到大，我都在一点点成长，进入这个世界。
Since I was a child I have been growing a little and entering this world.
desde chico me fui curtiendo un poco y entrando en este mundo.
但最重要的是，这让我有点震惊，因为我身边的人，因为我的女朋友等等。
But well, more than anything, it shocks me a little because of the people I have next to me, because of my girlfriend and so on.
Pero bueno, más que nada, me choca un poco por la gente que tengo al lado, por mi novia y demás.
我唯一尝试或想要的就是让他们健康，让他们受到保护，这对我来说是最重要的。
The only thing I try or want is for them to be well, for them to be protected and well that for me is the most important thing.
Yo lo único que intento o que quiero es que ellos estén bien, que estén protegidos y bueno eso para mí es lo más importante.
那么他们对我的评价不会改变我。
Then what they say about me doesn't change me.
después lo que puedan decir de mí no me cambia.
在我喜欢的那架飞机上。
in that plane that I like.
en ese plano que me gusta.
亚历克西斯是一个浪漫的人。
Alexis is a romantic.
Alexis es un romántico.
它有一种老套的感觉，所以它配上一些鲜花，配上一些巧克力，它就是一件古董。
It has a trite feel, so it falls with some flowers, with some chocolates, it is an antique.
Tiene un trillado, así cae con unas flores, con unos bombones, es una antigüedad.
或更多的写作我爱你，而事实是我不是很浪漫
or more of writing I love you and the truth is that I am not very romantic
o más de escribir te amo y la verdad que no soy muy romántico
我做我想做的事。
I do what comes my way.
Hago lo que me sale.
例如，前几天是我女朋友的生日，所以花...
For example, the other day was my girlfriend's birthday, so the flowers...
Por ejemplo, el otro día fue cumpleaños de mi novia, así las flores...
你要去训练，你给他留言说你今天过得愉快。
You're going to train and you leave him a message that you have a nice day.
te vas a entrenar y le dejas un mensajito que tengas un lindo día.
我有我的小事，但只是偶尔。
I have my little things, but very occasionally.
Tengo mis cositas, pero muy de vez en cuando.
我不会夸大你或对你撒谎。
I'm not going to get big or lie to you.
No me voy a agrandar ni a mentirles.
好吧，但是你正在考虑送一份特别的礼物，如果你听说他喜欢某样东西......
Ok, but you were thinking of giving a special gift, if you heard that he likes something...
Ok, pero pensabas hacer un regalo especial, de si escuchaste que le gusta algo...
我尝试了很多次。
I try that a lot.
Eso intento mucho.
嗯，这是我女朋友前几天告诉我的……
Well, that's what my girlfriend told me the other day...
Bueno, eso el otro día mi novia me decía...
对我来说，最重要的不是礼物本身，而是你倾听......
For me the most important thing is not the gift itself, but that you listened...
Para mí lo más importante no es el regalo en sí, sino que escuchaste...
我喜欢这个。
that I liked this.
que esto me gustaba.
我试着去关注这些事情，但有时它们会消失。
I try to pay attention to those things, but sometimes they get lost.
Esas cosas intento estar atentos, pero a veces se pierden.
你想要孩子吗？
Would you like to have children?
¿Te gustaría tener hijos?
是的，我愿意。
Yes I'd like to.
Sí, me gustaría.
你是...？
Are you...?
¿Ustedes son...?
三？
Three?
¿Tres?
我们是四个人。
We are four.
Nosotros somos cuatro.
三个男人和一个...
Three men and a...
Tres hombres y una...
从我父亲那里得知，她的名字是阿普丽尔。
From my dad, her name is April.
de parte de mi papá, se llama Abril.
你能想象自己在重复吗？
Can you imagine yourself repeating?
¿Te imaginas vos repitiendo?
不，没有那么多，没有那么多。
No, not so much, not so much.
No, tanto no, tanto no.
嗯，也许是三个。
Well, maybe three.
Bueno, capaz que tres.
我想我认为理想的数字是两个，但是嘿，也许是三个。
I think I see the ideal number as two, but hey, maybe three.
Yo creo que el número ideal lo veo en dos, pero bueno, capaz que tres.
我们现在已经接近两场了。
We are closing in two for now.
Vamos cerrando en dos por ahora.
移动。
moving.
moviendo.
我们还没有开始。
We haven't started yet.
Todavía no arrancamos.
不，我们没有开始，但很明显，我的想法是我想组建一个家庭，而且很好。
No, we didn't start but well obviously the idea is I want to start a family and well.
No, no arrancamos pero bueno obviamente que la idea está quiero formar una familia y bueno.
我和我女朋友也很幸福。
I am also very happy with my girlfriend.
Estoy muy contento también con mi novia.
既然进入了浪漫区，那么校园里有浪漫吗？
Since we're entering the romantic section, is there a romantic on campus?
Ya que entramos en tramo romanticismo, ¿hay un romántico del plantel?
一个黎明在那里说路易斯·米格尔我不知道我是否听了他那么多我不知道我是否听了他那么多
one that dawns there and says luis miguel I don't know if I listened to him that much I don't know if I listened to him that much
uno que por ahí amanece y pone luis miguel no sé si tanto no sé si tanto lo escuchaba
当时请罗德里发言并说他有他的……来自波尔的罗德里。
to Rodri to speak at the time and say that he has his... To Rodri from Pol.
a Rodri hablar en su momento y decir que tiene sus... A Rodri de Pol.
罗德里·德·波尔（Rodri de Pol），他有他的小事，但我不太清楚。
To Rodri de Pol and he has his little things, but I'm not very aware of it.
A Rodri de Pol y que tiene sus cositas, pero no estoy muy al tanto.
但我们不知道，你看，罗德里是什么样的，如果这是真的……
But we don't know, you see, what Rodri is like, if it's true...
Pero no sabemos, viste, cómo es Rodri, si es verdad...
是的，我是最浪漫的，就是这样。
Yes, I am the most romantic and just like that.
Si yo soy el más romántico y tal cual.
你卖得好吗？
Do you sell it well?
¿La vende bien?
他卖得好，他卖得好。
He sells it well, he sells it well.
La vende bien, la vende bien.
但我们无法证实这一点。
But well, we can't confirm it.
Pero bueno, no lo podemos confirmar.
听我说，最烦人的...
Listen to me, the most annoying...
Escúchame, el más molesto...
团体中，最搞笑的。
of the group, the funniest.
del grupo, el más jodón.
最烦人的是尼科·冈萨雷斯。
And the most annoying would be Nico González.
Y el más molesto te diría Nico González.
现在我有点想念它了。
Now I'm missing it a little bit.
Ahora lo estoy extrañando un poquito.
是的，尼科是一个可怕的角色。
Yes, Nico is a terrible character.
Sí, Nico es un personaje terrible.
所以他把一切都搞砸了。
So he screws everything up.
Así que hace joditas todo.
是的，他是一个人物。
Yes, he is a character.
Sí, es un personaje.
比较安静的意思是，你还好吗？
The quieter one means, are you okay?
El más callado quiere decir, ¿estás bien?
你必须一直问他是否还好。
You have to ask him all the time if he is okay.
Hay que preguntarle todo el tiempo si está bien.
沃尔特·贝尼特斯可能也在场。
Walter Benítez may be there.
Ahí puede estar Walter Benítez.
我也很冷静。
I'm also pretty calm.
Yo también soy bastante tranquilo.
我也有这样的时候，但我很平静。
I have moments, but I'm pretty calm.
Tengo momentos, pero soy bastante tranquilo.
你能和自己的孤独相处吗？
Do you get along well with your loneliness?
¿Te llevas bien con tu soledad?
是的，我喜欢一个人呆着。
Yes, I like to be alone.
Sí, me gusta estar solo.
明显地...
Obviously...
Obviamente...
短期内独自一人，但我喜欢它，我确实认为它很好。
short terms being alone, but I like it, I do think it's good.
cortos plazos estar solo, pero me gusta, sí creo que está bueno.
听我说，在他们完成了所有的事情之后，
Listen to me, after all they accomplished,
Escúchame, después de todo lo que lograron,
你还看到什么？
What else do you see?
¿Qué más ves vos?
你还想要什么？
What else would you like?
¿Qué más te gustaría?
你认为自己会在利物浦效力多年吗？
Do you see yourself at Liverpool for years?
¿Te ves años en el Liverpool?
你认为自己处于另一个联盟吗？
Do you see yourself in another league?
¿Te ves en otra liga?
您认为自己会成为新的冠军吗？
Do you see yourself becoming a new champion?
¿Te ves campeonando nuevo?
不，让我们看看，显然我们为利物浦效力......
No, let's see, obviously playing for Liverpool we have...
No, a ver, obviamente jugando para Liverpool tenemos...
非常重要的目标，比如英超联赛和欧冠联赛。
Very important objectives, such as the Premier League and the Champions League.
Objetivos muy importantes, como lo son la Premier League y la Champions.
我认为这两个标题可能是
I think those two titles are perhaps the
Creo que esos dos títulos quizás son los
我今天指出的那些。
the ones I point out today.
los que apunto hoy en día.
但是，嘿，我总是准备好参加比赛并赢得我力所能及的一切。
But hey, I always prepare to play and win whatever is within my reach.
Pero bueno, yo siempre me preparo para jugar y ganar lo que esté al alcance.
我认为这是最重要的事情，并为此而奋斗。
And I think that's the most important thing and to fight for that.
Y creo que eso es lo más importante y luchar por eso.
但是，是的，如果你问我主观的话......
But yeah, if you ask me subjective...
Pero sí, si me preguntas subjetivos...
我会称你为英超冠军，显然我在利物浦很开心并且很享受。
I would call you Premier League Champion and obviously I am very happy in Liverpool and enjoying myself.
Te diría Premier League Champion y obviamente que estoy muy contento en Liverpool y disfrutando.
它们是很好的目标。
They are good objectives.
Son buenos objetivos.
英语水平，我们怎么样？
English level, how are we?
Nivel de inglés, ¿cómo estamos?
绘制级别，为 10。
Draw level, which is a 10.
Nivel Dibu, que es un 10.
不，低一点，低一点。
No, a little lower, a little lower.
No, un poquito más abajo, un poquito más abajo.
事实上，英国人非常赞扬我。
The people, the truth is, who praise me a lot, the English.
La gente, la verdad, que me lo alaga mucho, el inglés.
尤其是发音。
Especially the pronunciations.
Sobre todo las pronunciaciones.
我已经在那里呆了五年了。
I've been there for five years now.
Yo ya llevo cinco años allá.
你会说英语，对吗？
You speak English, right?
Hablas inglés, ¿no?
你看，我尝试将英式英语融入其中，包括一些发音。
And I try, you see, to put British English into it, some pronunciations.
Y intento, viste, meterle el inglés británico, alguna que otra pronunciación.
但一开始对我来说有点困难。
But it was a bit difficult for me at first.
Pero me costó un poco al principio.
我已经半胖了
I'm half fat.
Soy medio engordado.
尴尬的是，我不想犯错误，直到我开始放松一点，一切都不好了。
embarrassing, I didn't want to make mistakes until I started to loosen up a little and nothing was good.
vergonzoso, no quería cometer errores hasta que me empecé a soltar un poquito y nada bien.
我让自己被理解。
I make myself understood.
me hago entender.
当你犯错误并与别人交谈时，你会学到东西，并看到对方如何无意中纠正你，因为他们在谈话中。
You learn when you make mistakes and talk to someone else and see how the other person accidentally corrects you because they are in the conversation.
Vas aprendiendo cuando cometes errores y hablas con otro y ves como el otro lo corrige sin querer porque está en la conversación.
就这样，我跟随一位老师学习了一年半。
As is and apart, I studied for a year and a half with a teacher.
Tal cual y aparte yo estudié un año y medio con una profesora.
我觉得我学到了很多东西，但在实践中你最终会发现最多的错误等等。
I feel like I learned a lot, but in practice is where you end up realizing the most mistakes and so on.
que siento que aprendí un montón, pero en la práctica es donde más te terminas dando cuenta de los errores y demás.
我们要关门了。
We are closing.
Vamos cerrando.
我想让你为我定义一下这种感觉。
I want you to define the sensation for me.
Quiero que me definas la sensación.
一个字，就是世界冠军的感觉。
a single word, the feeling of being world champion.
una sola palabra, la sensación de ser campeón del mundo.
在您看来，哪个词可以定义成为世界冠军？
What word defines being a world champion in your feelings?
¿Qué palabra define en tus sentimientos ser campeón del mundo?
是...
Y...
我认为骄傲。
I think pride.
Yo creo que orgullo.
骄傲……我喜欢吗？
Pride... Do I like it?
Orgullo... ¿Me gusta?
是的，一切都一点点，一点点......
Yes, a little for everything, a little for...
Sí, un poco por todo, un poco por...
就我个人而言，嘿，我一直工作是为了......
Personally, to say, hey, I worked all this time to...
en lo personal de decir, che, trabajé todo este tiempo para...
实现重要的事情并赢得世界杯，然后也是为了我们所带来的……
to achieve important things and win a World Cup and then also for what we brought to...
para lograr cosas importantes y ganar una Copa del Mundo y después también por lo que trajimos a...
回到祖国，我认为这是……巨大的快乐。
to the country, which I think was... An immense joy.
al país, que creo que eso fue... Un alegría inmensa.
是的，我总是这么说，我们在公共汽车上度过的那天，所有人都在那里，我认为这是......
Yes, I always said it, the day we spent with the bus and all the people were there, I think it was one of the...
Sí, siempre lo dije, el día que pasamos con el micro y estaba toda la gente, creo que fue uno de los...
我一生中最幸福的日子。
of the happiest days of my life.
de los días más felices de mi vida.
五百万人涌上街头。
Five million people in the streets.
Cinco millones de personas en la calle.
太疯狂了。
It was crazy.
Fue una locura.
没见过。
Never seen.
Nunca visto.
我不知道，疯了。
I don't know, crazy.
No sé, una locura.
此外，人们在公共汽车旁边奔跑。
And besides, people were running next to the bus.
Y aparte que la gente corría al lado del micro.
不，不，疯狂，那一天太疯狂了，令人难忘。
No, no, madness, that day was crazy, unforgettable.
No, no, la locura, ese día fue una locura, inolvidable.
亚历克西斯，关于这一部分的最后一个被理想地切碎的人。
Alexis, the last one regarding this section that is ideally chopped.
Alexis, la última con respecto a esta sección que es picadito ideal.
你必须去玩一场理想的碎游戏。
You have to go play an ideal minced game.
Tenés que ir a jugar un picadito ideal.
那么就是你和另外四个人的选择，你的家庭兄弟父亲月的生活选择和
then it's you and four more of the selection of the selection of the life of your family brother father month and the
entonces sos vos y cuatro más de la selección de la selección de la vida de tu familia hermano padre mes y el
但如果它属于我的家人，我就必须把我的家人放进去，否则他们会让我生气。
But if it belongs to my family I have to put my family in it, otherwise they will make me angry.
Pero si es de mi familia tengo que poner a mi familia, si no se me enojan.
也就是说，你理想中的肉末，谁来就跟谁比……
In other words, your ideal minced meat, let's play against whoever comes...
O sea, tu picadito ideal, vamos a jugar contra el que venga...
麦卡利斯特家族。
The Macalisters.
Los Macalister.
而且...这是一档真人秀节目，Macalisters。
And... It's a reality show, the Macalisters.
Y... Es un reality, los Macalister.
他们把他们三人放在一起，然后我们加上里奥，以免漏掉他，里奥·梅西。
They put the three of them and then we add Leo so as not to leave him out, Leo Messi.
que ponen a ellos tres y después le agregamos a Leo como para no dejarlo afuera, Leo Messi.
我，如果你，带着它。
I, if you, carry it.
Yo que vos lo llevo.
当然，我们就在那里，我们有四个人，利奥，五个人，我们已经在那里了。
And of course, there we are, there are four of us, Leo, five, we're already there.
Y claro, ahí estamos, somos cuatro, Leo, cinco, ya estamos.
你们四个还有梅西。
You four and Messi.
Ustedes cuatro y Messi.
我们派凯文去进球，他的进球能力非常好。
We sent Kevin to goal, he is very good in goal.
Nos mandamos a Kevin al arco, es muy bueno en el arco.
操我。
Fuck me.
Jodeme.
当我们比赛时，进球非常好。
The goal is very good when we play.
Muy bueno el arco cuando jugamos.
足球爸爸，对吗？
Soccer daddy, right?
Papi fútbol, ¿no?
是的，足球爸爸，我们小时候踢球的时候，你知道他是怎么救球的吗？
Yes, soccer dad, when we played when we were little, do you know how he saved?
Sí, papi fútbol, cuando jugábamos de chiquitos, ¿sabes cómo atajaba?
好信息。
Good information.
Buen dato.
糟糕的。
Terrible.
所以我们派凯恩射门。
So we sent Kane to goal.
Así que lo mandamos a Kane al arco.
哈维尔和弗朗西娅在后面，稍微组织一下一切，我在中间，利奥在上面。
Javier and Francia in the back, organizing everything a little, me in the middle and Leo on top.
Javier y Francia atrás, ordenando un poco todo, yo en el medio y Leo arriba.
这里我就过去了。
Here I pass.
Aquí paso.
听我说，我有来自我的 mateampa 朋友的礼物，官方 mateampa 在整个市场上排名第一，这是给你的
well listen to me I have gifts from my matepampa friends official matepampa made number one in the total market this one is for you
bueno escuchame tengo regalos de mis amigos de matepampa matepampa oficial hizo número uno en el mercado total este es para vos
一切都经过精心调整。
Everything is spectacularly tuned.
Está todo tuneado espectacular.
我将打开它来帮助你。
I'm going to open it for you to help you.
Te lo voy a abrir para ayudarte.
就像这个说的那样。
Like this one that says.
Como este que dice.
世界冠军。
World Champions.
Campeones del mundo.
在这里，这就是帖子。
Here, this is the post.
Acá, esta es la posta.
阿列克西·马卡利瑟，世界冠军。
Alexi Makálitser, world champion.
Alexi Makálitser, campeón del mundo.
潘帕为你准备了这份礼物。
Pampa made this gift for you.
Pampa hizo este regalo para ustedes.
不需要治疗，没什么。
There is no need to cure it, nothing.
No hay que curarlo, nada.
热气腾腾，蔚为壮观。
Thermal, spectacular.
Térmico, espectacular.
哦，完美。
Oh, perfect.
Ah, perfecto.
成功了。
A success.
Un éxito.
托马斯已经满员了。
Tomás mate at full.
Tomás mate a full.
一整天。
All day.
Todo el día.
你会发现自己正在向一位英国女孩、一名记者展示你是如何做到的。
You will find yourself demonstrating to an English girl, a journalist, how you did it.
Te verás demostrándole a una chica inglesa, una periodista, cómo lo hacías.
对我来说英语有点复杂，对吧？
It was a bit complicated for me with English, right?
Se me complicó un poco con el inglés, ¿no?
听着，你没有活着。
Listen, you don't live.
Escucha, no te vives.
还有这个？
And this one?
¿Y este?
这是米奇老鼠的迪士尼马特奥·潘帕 (Mateo Pampa) 的特别版，送给你的女朋友。
which is a special edition of Mateo Pampa from Disney, from Mickey Mouse, for your girlfriend.
que es una edición especial de Mateo Pampa de Disney, de Mickey Mouse, para tu novia.
非常好。
Very good.
Muy bien.
完美的。
Perfect.
Perfecto.
告诉他你也不会和这个人发生浪漫的事。
Tell him that you are not going to get romantic with this one either.
Decirle que tampoco te vas a hacer romántico con este.
告诉他是我给你的。
Tell him that I gave it to you.
Decirle que te lo regalé yo.
不要在相机上展示它，所以我买给你什么的。
Don't show it on camera so I bought it for you or something.
No lo saquen en cámara así de que se lo compré o algo.
亚历克西斯，一种疯狂的快乐。
Alexis, a crazy pleasure.
Alexis, un placer loco.
我从心底里祝贺你，我钦佩你，你是天才。
I congratulate you from the bottom of my heart, I admire you, you are geniuses.
Te felicito de corazón, te admiro, son unos genios.
对于一切，行为、教育、榜样，事实是它们都是现象，它们应该得到最好的。
For everything, behavior, education, example, the truth is they are phenomena, they deserve the best.
Por todo, comportamiento, educación, ejemplo, la verdad son unos fenómenos, se merecen lo mejor.
嗯，非常感谢。
Well, thank you very much.
Bueno, muchísimas gracias.
亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特，随机信息，阿根廷国家队特别轮。
Alexis McAllister, Random Infobah, Special Round of the Argentine National Team.
Alexis McAllister, Infobah de Random, Tanda Especial de la Selección Argentina.